Kristin De Salme

Phone: (210) 445-2192 | Email: kristin.desalme@gmail.com | San Antonio, TX

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristin-desalme/ Portfolio: https://kr1istin.github.io/portfolio react/

GitHub: https://github.com/KR1ISTIN

As a FullStack developer and dental hygienist, I offer excellent communication and teamwork skills, along with a keen eagerness and willingness to learn on this journey. The transition from oral health care to programming may seem unexpected, but I thrive on challenges, and web development provides the perfect canvas. I look forward to contributing my diverse experiences and enthusiasm to a new team and making a meaningful impact in the field.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML5, BASH
- Frameworks/Libraries: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Node.js, Express.js, React, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Bulma, Tailwind
- Databases: PostGresQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose
- Tools/Technologies: RESTful APIs, Maven, Docker, Microservices, JWT, OAuth2, Bycrpt, GraphQL, Jest, Object-oriented programming, Heroku, Git, IntelliJ, pgAdmin4, MySQL Workbench, MVC Pattern
- **Project Management:** Team Collaboration, Communication, Agile Development, Scrum, Sprint, Kanban, Jira, Github Projects, Wireframming, GithubActions CI Pipeline
- AWS: IAM, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, AWS RDS, S3

EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer ARP Roofing and Remodeling

2024-Present Remote

Contracted to create an app that is a central source for customer related data.

Key Accomplishments/In Progress:

- Reduced latency in lead creation by enabling sales reps to quickly input leads on the go.
- Implementing a central customer MySQL database with access for customer manipulation.
- Reduced operational debt by integrating multiple systems together.
- Implementing User Authentication with Bycrpt, JWT, Sessions.

Volunteering to help a childhood cancer nonprofit. Built a key-single page featuring update operations, database consultation and implementation, and mentoring in Git versioning control.

Key Accomplishments:

- Collaborated with team to refine database architecture, enduring efficiency.
- Successfully trained my partner in Git versioning control, fostering collaborative and efficient development environments.
- Successfully implemented Update operations using Django and Python for user implementation.
- Successfully implemented BootStrap for the user interview when updating account information.

Dental Hygienist TruSmile Dentistry

2017-Present San Antonio, TX

2023-Present

Remote

Perform dental cleanings and educate patients on how to maintain excellent oral hygiene.

Key Accomplishments:

- Established a strong rapport with patients through active listening, empathetic communication, and personalized care, nurturing trust and comfort that contributed to improved patient cooperation and dental experience.
- Collaboration with dental colleagues, sharing insights and providing assistance in complex cases, thereby creating a cohesive team environment that improved patient care and satisfaction.
- Took *leadership* of training my colleagues, teaching the important skills and knowledge which elevated the team's expertise and provided a more valuable workflow
- Moved to lead hygienist after 1.5 years

PROJECTS

MealMappr

Github Repo Link

Deployed Link to MealMappr

MealMappr, a team project, that allows access for users to manage their personalized meal plans.

Role: FullStack and Project Management

Implemented Models, Routes for CRUD both front and backend, Login/Logout functionality, Scrum Master, UI design for modal pop up

Tools/Technologies: Heroku, HTML, JavaScript, Node, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, TailWind, Full Calendar, Bycrpt, Team Collaboration, Agile Development, KanBan, Scrum, Paired Programming, Git, Github Projects, Wireframe

YardGems

Github Repo Link

Deployed Link to YardGems

YardGems, a team project, utilizing the MERN Stack. It allows users to search and post garage sales.

Role: FullStack and Project Management

Implemented React Google Maps API, Models, GraphQL, Routes for CRUD both front and backend, Login/Logout functionality, UI design for creating and updating post, Scrum Master

Tools/Technologies: React, React Router DOM, Heroku, Mongoose, JavaScript, React Google Maps API, GraphQL, MaterialUI, Express.js, Node.js, Apollo Server, JWT, Bycrpt, HTML, CSS, Team Collaboration, Agile Development, Kanban, Scrum, Paired Programming, Git, Github Projects, Wireframe

EDUCATION

Certificate, Master Java, Spring 6 and Spring Boot 3 with JDBC, JPA,

May 2024

Security, Docker and Microservices with Telusko

A 42-hour course in mastering Java, Spring, Spring Boot, JPA, AOP, with the addition of Docker and Microservices.

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development: UTSA

July 2023

A 24-week, project driven course, in full stack JavaScript Web Development Certification.

Associate, Dental Hygiene: Concorde Career College

May 2017

A 18-month accelerated program, focusing on oral hygiene and clinical care.

Diploma, Dental Assisting: Concorde Career College

Feb 2014